Guide to the Research Institute for the Study of Man (RISM) Vertical Files RISM.VF.1
New York University Archives
- Dominica (Box 9)
  - Dominica: Mental Health (Box 9)
    - Mind Out!: Mental Health is Vital to Man, Women & Child, 1967; RISM 15098; Dominica Association for Mental Health; 27.0 (Box 9)
      Mental health.; Dominica.
  - Dominica: Military Assistance, America (Box 9)
    - Peacekeeping; Agreement Between the United States of America and Dominica, 1983-1984; RISM 20595; United States. Department of State; 4 pages (Box 9)
      Dominica.; Military assistance American.
  - Dominica: National Parks and Reserves (Box 9)
    - The Cabrits of Dominica: A Tour Guide, undated; RISM 20596; 4 pages (Box 9)
      Dominica.; National parks and reserves.
    - Dominica's National Park: Concept and Purposes, 1978; RISM 20597; Honychurch, Penelope N. (Penelope Narodny); 10 pages (Box 9)
    - National Parks from the Ground Up: Experience from Dominica, West Indies, 1984; RISM 20598; Thorsell, J. W.; p. 615-619. (Box 9)
    - After God the Earth: Rain Forest Preserved in Dominica, West Indies, 1975; Wright, R. Michael; 4 pages (Box 9)
  - Dominica: Natural History (Box 9)
    - A Naturalist's Excursion in Dominica, 1985; RISM 20599; Johow, Friedrich; p. 679-687. (Box 9)
      Dominica.; Natural history.
  - Dominica: Peasantry (Box 9)
    - Notes on a Caribbean Peasant Community in Dominica, British West Indies, 1957; RISM 20600; McKusick, Marshall, 1879-1950; 14 pages (Box 9)
      Dominica.; Peasants.
  - Dominica: Poetry (Box 9)
    - Words in the Quiet Moments, 1981; RISM 23002; John, Giftus R., 1954-; 21 pages (Box 9)
      Poetry.; Dominica.
  - Dominica: Police (Box 9)
    - Report on the Dominica Police Force, 1963-1966; RISM 20601; Dominica Police Force; 2 items; 1963, 1966; no content (Box 9)
      Police.; Dominica.
  - Dominica: Political Parties (Box 9)
    - The Programme of the Labour Party of Dominica, undated; RISM 20603; 5 pages (Box 9)
      Dominica.; Political parties.
    - Working People Understand Dominica Lessons, undated; Working People's Alliance Guyana; 1 page (Box 9)
      Political parties.; Dominica.
  - Dominica: Prisons (Box 9)
    - Report on the Treatment of Offenders for the Year, 1954-1957; RISM 20604; Dominica. Keeper of the Prisons; 3 items; 1954, 1956, 1957; no content (Box 9)
      Dominica.; Prisons.
  - Dominica: Public Health (Box 9)
    - Environmental Modification and Changing Health Practices, 1968; RISM 20607; Morris, Miriam; 12 pages (Box 9)
      Public health.; Dominica.
  - Dominica: Real Property Tax (Box 9)
    - Property Taxes: A Potential Revenue Source for Dominica?, 1987; RISM 24933; Lewis, Wilfred; 8 pages (Box 9)
      Dominica.; Real property tax.
  - Dominica: Soils (Box 9)
    - Dominica's National Park: Geology and Soils, 1978; RISM 20608; Honychurch, Penelope N. (Penelope Narodny); 16 pages (Box 9)
      Soils.; Dominica.
    - The Major Agricultural Land Types in Dominica, West Indies and their Potential for Development, 1972; RISM 20609; Shillingford, J. D. (John Davison), 1940-; 26 pages (Box 9)
  - Dominica: Taxation (Box 9)
    - Taxation: Exchange of Information; Agreement Between the United States of America and Dominica, 1987; RISM 20610; United States. Department of State; 9 pages (Box 9)
      Taxation.; Dominica.
  - Dominica: Tropical Plants (Box 9)
    - Dominica's National Park: Vegetation, 1978; RISM 20611; Honychurch, Penelope N. (Penelope Narodny); 25 pages (Box 9)
      Dominica.; Tropical plants.
  - Dominica: Water Supply (Box 9)
    - Dominica's National Park: Water, 1978; RISM 20612; Honychurch, Penelope N. (Penelope Narodny); 10 pages (Box 9)
      Water-supply.; Dominica.
  - Dominica: Women (Box 9)
    - Planning for Women in Rural Development: The Tans-G-Toc Cooperative of Dominica, ca. 1986; RISM 20613; John, Noreen; p. 48-60. (Box 9)
      Dominica.; Women.
- Dominican Republic (Box 9)
  - Dominican Republic: Agricultural Assistance, American (Box 9)
    - Agricultural Sector Loan; Agreement Between the United States of America and the Dominican Republic, 1977; RISM 16696; United States. Treaties, etc., Dominican Republic, Apr. 7, 1977; 31 pages (Box 9)
      Dominican Republic.; Agricultural assistance, American.
  - Dominican Republic: Agriculture (Box 9)
    - La Produccion de Tomates Para la Industria en la Linea Noroeste, 1967; RISM 16716; Smith, Leon R.; 7 pages (Box 9)
      Agriculture.; Dominican Republic.
    - Informacion Basica Sobre Metodos y Practicas de Meradeo Observados en el Mercade Modelo y en el Hospedaje, 1966; RISM 16717; Marshall, Garland R.; 10 pages (Box 9)
      Dominican Republic.; Agriculture.
    - Un Estudio Socio-Economico de un Area Agricola en la Provincia de Monte Cristi, 1966; RISM 16718; Marshall, Garland R.; 10 pages (Box 9)
    - Small Farmer Associations and Development Programs: Case of the Dominican Republic, 1976; RISM 24334; University of Wisconsin--Madison. Land Tenure Center; p. 14-22. (Box 9)
  - Dominican Republic: Airlines (Box 9)
    Airlines |z Dominican Republic.
    - Aviation Assistance; Memorandum of Agreement Between the United States of America and the Dominican Republic, 1988; RISM 16766; United States. Department of State; 11 pages (Box 9)
      Dominican Republic.; Airlines.
  - Dominican Republic: Anthropology (Box 9)
    - Hacia una Anthropologia Dominicana, 1978; RISM 23986; Davis, Martha Ellen; 25 pages (Box 9)
      Dominican Republic.; Anthropology.
  - Dominican Republic: Carnival (Box 9)
    - Social Functions of Carnival in a Dominican City, 1970; RISM 17525; González, Nancie L. Solien, 1929- (Box 9)
      Dominican Republic.; Carnival.
  - Dominican Republic: Church and State (Box 9)
    - La Iglesia Catalica en el Pensamiento Constitucional Dominicano, 1984; RISM 17453; Pérez Memén, Fernando, 1943-; 19 pages (Box 9)
      Dominican Republic.; Church and state.
  - Dominican Republic: Constitution (Box 9)
    - Constitution of the Dominican Republic, 1966, 1971; RISM 20614; Organization of American States. General Secretariat; 28 pages (Box 9)
      Dominican Republic.; Constitutional history.
  - Dominican Republic: Cultural Pluralism (Box 9)
    - Constanza: A Heterogeneous Society in the Dominican Republic, 1970; RISM 17806; Walker, Malcolm T.; 20 pages (Box 9)
      Dominican Republic.; Cultural pluralism.
    - Composicion Social Dominicana, 1970; 1 page (Box 11)
      Cultural pluralism.; Dominican Republic.
  - Dominican Republic: Description and Travel (Box 9)
    - Informe Sobre la Republica Dominicana, 1962; RISM 17800; Maldonado-Denis, Manuel, 1933-; 15 pages (Box 9)
      Dominican Republic.
    - Country Profiles: Dominican Republic, 1973; RISM 17801; Perez Montâs, Hernando; 7 pages (Box 9)
    - Dominican Republic, 1958; RISM 17802; Pan American Union; 31 pages (Box 9)
    - Background Notes: Dominican Republic, 1978-2000; RISM 17803; United States. Department of State. Bureau of Western Hemisphere Affairs; 3 items; 10/78, 10/81, 10/00; no content (Box 9)
    - Focus: The Dominican Republic, 1965; RISM 17804; American Geographical Society of New York; 6 pages (Box 9)
    - Introduction to Dominican Republic, 1959; RISM 17805; Pan American Union; 2 pages (Box 9)
    - Dominican Republic, 2000; RISM 26334; 8 pages; 8.0 (Box 9)
  - Dominican Republic: Economic Conditions (Box 9)
    - Foreign Trade Regulations of the Dominican Republic, 1968; RISM 17819; Haidar, Walter; 5 pages (Box 9)
      Economic conditions.; Dominican Republic.
    - Marketing in the Dominican Republic, 1980-1989; RISM 17820; United States. Office of International Trade; 2 items; 1980, 1989; no content (Box 9)
    - Investing in the Dominican Republic, 1986; RISM 17821; Caribbean/Central American Action (Organization); 18 pages (Box 9)
    - El Futuro Dominicano, 1980; RISM 23143; Moya Pons, Frank, 1944-; 18 pages (Box 9)
      Dominican Republic.; Economic conditions.
    - La Reforma Financiera en la Republica Dominicana, undated; RISM 17816; Alvarez Betancourt, Opinio (Box 9)
    - Trade: Tokyo Round of the Multilateral Negotiations; Agreement Between the United States and the Dominican Republic, 1979-1980; RISM 17817; United States. Department of State; 8 pages (Box 9)
    - Foreign Economic Trends and Their Implications for the United States: Dominican Republic, 1977-1989; RISM 17818; United States. Office of International Trade; 3 items; 1977, 1988, 1989; no content (Box 9)
    - Empresarios en Conflicto, Politicas de Industrializacion y Sustitucion de Importaciones en la Republica Dominicana, 1992; RISM 23145; Miguel Bonetti, José; 12 pages (Box 9)
    - Variaciones Sobre un Tema de Desarrollo Economico, 1977; RISM 23963; Canela, Luis A.; 7 pages (Box 9)
  - Dominican Republic: Education (Box 9)
    - Radio Santa Maria: Una Radiomisora Educativa y Cultural: Limitaciones, Posibilidades y Filosofia, 1976; RISM 23723; p. 178-239. (Box 9)
      Education.; Dominican Republic.
    - Encuesta Acerca de la Audiencia de la Escuela Radiofonica de Educacion Familiar de la Asociacion Dominicana Pro Bienestar de la Familia, Inc., 1976; RISM 23003; Ortega, Manuel M., 1932-; 32 pages (Box 9)
      Dominican Republic.; Education.
  - Dominican Republic: Education, Higher (Box 9)
    - Higher Education and Development in the Dominican Republic, 1984; RISM 17865; Edmisten, Patricia Taylor; 13 pages (Box 9)
      Dominican Republic.; Education, Higher.
  - Dominican Republic: Elections (Box 9)
    - El Comportamiento Electoral Dominicano: Un Analysis Comparado de las Elecciones de 1978 y 1982, 1983; RISM 17998; Castillo, Jos‌ del; 15 pages (Box 9)
      Dominican Republic.; Elections.
  - Dominican Republic: Ethnobotany (Box 9)
    - Notas y Entrevistas Sobre Etnobotanica en Santo Domingo, 1972; RISM 24038; González, María Filomena; p. 131-167. (Box 9)
      Ethnobotany.; Dominican Republic.
  - Dominican Republic: Fertility, Human (Box 9)
    - The Dominican Republic Fertility Survey: A Summary of Findings, 1977; RISM 18117; 7 pages (Box 9)
      Dominican Republic.; Fertility, Human.
  - Dominican Republic: Food Industry and Trade (Box 9)
    - Dominican Republic: Factors Affecting Its Capacity to Import Food, 1983; RISM 18210; Bolling, H. Christine; 25 pages (Box 9)
      Food industry and trade; Dominican Republic.
  - Dominican Republic: Foreign Relations, United States (Box 9)
    - Marines in Santo Domingo!, 1965; RISM 15756; Perlo, Victor; 31 pages; ill.; 20 cm. (Box 9)
      Dominican Republic.; International relations.; United States.
    - Smoldering Conflict: Dominican Republic, 1965-1975, RISM 17826; North American Congress on Latin America; 32 pages (Box 9)
  - Dominican Republic: Geology (Box 9)
    - Caribbean Eocene Volcanism and the Extent of Horizon A, 1971; RISM 18487; Mattson, Peter H.; p. 128-129 (Box 9)
      Dominican Republic.; Geology.
    - Scientific Cooperation: Geological Sciences; Memorandum of Understanding Between the United States of America and the Dominican Republic, 1984; RISM 20619; United States. Department of State; 11 pages (Box 9)
      Geology.; Dominican Republic.
    - Emerged and Submerged Shorelines of the Dominican Republic, 1962; RISM 23150; Barrett, W.; p. 53-77 (Box 9)
  - Dominican Republic: Haitians (Box 9)
    - Haitian Labor: Dominicans Rely On It, undated; RISM 24153; Meslin, Richard J.; 1 page (Box 9)
      Haitians; Dominican Republic.
  - Dominican Republic: History (Box 9)
    - Breve Historia Dominicana: Una Sintesis Critica, 1982; RISM 17838; Mejía-Ricart G., Tirso (Mejía-Ricart Guzmán), 1936-; 48 pages (Box 9)
      History.; Dominican Republic.
    - Raices Latinoamericanistas del Nacionalismo Dominicano, 1983; RISM 17839; Franco, Franklin J. (Box 9)
    - El Febrerismo Ayer y Hoy, 1983; RISM 17840; Franco, Franklin J. (Box 9)
      Dominican Republic.; History.
    - La Ensenanza de la Historia Patria, 1981; RISM 17841; Franco, Franklin J.; 20 pages (Box 9)
    - Nota Sobre la Cultura Dominicana, 1979; RISM 24012; Deive, Carlos Esteban, 1935-; p. 293-305. (Box 9)
  - Dominican Republic: Indians of the Caribbean (Box 9)
    - La Sociedad Taina, 1973; RISM 20620; Moya Pons, Frank, 1944-; 22 pages (Box 9)
      Indians of the West Indies.; Dominican Republic.
    - Del Mito al Tiempo Sagrado un Posible Calendario Agricola: Ceremonial Taino, 1981; RISM 23247; Robiou Lamarche, Sebastián (Box 9)
      Dominican Republic.; Indians of the West Indies.
    - Datos Para el Estudio de la Demografia Aborigen en Santo Domingo, 1979; RISM 24187; Moya Pons, Frank, 1944-; 11 pages (Box 9)
    - Aspectos Etnologicos Aborigenes y Actuales, del Uso de la Guayiga y sus Derivados en Santo Domingo, 1973; RISM 24284; Veloz Maggiolo, Marcio; p. 33-39. (Box 9)
  - Dominican Republic: Industrialization (Box 9)
    - Empresarios en Conflicto: Politicas de Industrializacion y Sustitucion de Importaciones en la Republica Dominicana, 1992; RISM 23040; Moya Pons, Frank, 1944-; unpaged. (Box 9)
      Industrialization.; Dominican Republic.
  - Dominican Republic: Jews (Box 9)
    - Presencia Hebrea en la Republica Dominicana, 1974; RISM 24318; Dujarric, Enrique de Marchena; p. 17-25. (Box 9)
      Dominican Republic.; Jews.
  - Dominican Republic: Labor and Laboring Classes (Box 9)
    - Foreign Labor Trends: Dominican Republic, 1988-1991; RISM 20621; United States. Bureau of International Labor Affairs; 2 items; 1988/89, 1990/91; no content (Box 9)
      Labor and laboring classes.; Dominican Republic.
  - Dominican Republic: Music (Box 9)
    - Aspectos de la Influencia Africana en la Musica Tradicional Dominicana, 1980; RISM 23985; Davis, Martha Ellen; p. 255-292. (Box 9)
      Dominican Republic.; Music.
  - Dominican Republic: Patronage, Political (Box 9)
    - Power Structure and Patronage in a Community of the Dominican Republic, 1970; RISM 20623; Walker, Malcolm T.; p. 485-504. (Box 9)
      Dominican Republic.; Patronage, Political.
  - Dominican Republic: Politics and Government (Box 9)
    - The Dominican Republic: The Politics of Chaos, 1969; RISM 17815; Lowenthal, Abraham F.; p. 34-58 (Box 9)
      Dominican Republic.; Politics and government.
    - Americo Lugo: El Patriota Olvidado, 1984; RISM 17824; Balcácer, Juan Daniel, 1949-; 23 pages (Box 9)
    - De Balaguer a Guzman, 1982; RISM 17825; Concepción, J. Agustín, 1906-; 32 pages (Box 9)
      Politics and government.; Dominican Republic.
    - New Events Inspire Regroupment: Interview with Socialist Bloc Leader, 1984; RISM 23144; Rivera, Octavio; 2 pages (Box 9)
    - The Hispanic Caribbean: Dominican Republic - Insular Nationalism and Economic Dependence, undated; RISM 23995; De Onis, Juan, 1927-; 18 pages (Box 9)
  - Dominican Republic: Population (Box 9)
    - Estudios de Poblacion en la Republica Dominicana: Realizaciones y Prioridades, 1977; RISM 20618; Ortega, Manuel M., 1932-; 11 pages (Box 9)
      Dominican Republic.; Population.
    - Como se Vive en un Barrio de Santiago, 1967; RISM 23136; Garcia, Cesar; 13 pages (Box 9)
    - Acciones Prioriatrias en Materia de Investigacion en Poblacion en la Republica Dominicana, 1977; RISM 24039; González Fabra, Luis; 7 pages (Box 9)
    - Una Seleccion Bibliografica Sobrea Poblacion en la Republic Dominicana: Version Preliminar, 1972; RISM 24194; Ortega, Manuel M., 1932-; p. 53-85. (Box 9)
    - Racial Classifications of the Seventeenth and Eighteenth Centuries, 1944; RISM 23308; Slotkin, James Sydney, 1913-1958; p. 459-467. (Box 9)
  - Dominican Republic: Postal Service (Box 9)
    - Postal: Express Mail Service; Agreement Between the United States of America and the Dominican Republic, 1990-1991; RISM 20624; United States. Department of State; 13 pages (Box 9)
      Postal service.; Dominican Republic.
  - Dominican Republic: Rice (Box 9)
    - Women Don't Grow Rice; Or Do They...?: Feminization and Defeminization in Dominican Agriculture - The Case of Female Rice Farming in Land Reform Areas, 1984; RISM 20625; Box, L.; 18 pages (Box 9)
      Dominican Republic.; Rice.
  - Dominican Republic: Social Science Research (Box 9)
    - Financiamiento y Administracion de la Investigacion, 1977; RISM 24031; Garcia T., Ezequiel; 11 pages (Box 9)
      Dominican Republic.; Research (document genres).; Social sciences.
    - La Ciencia Politica en la Republica Dominicana Problemas y Perspectivas, 1977; RISM 24315; Brea-Franco, Julio, 1948-; 9 pages (Box 9)
      Dominican Republic.; Social sciences.; Research (document genres).
  - Dominican Republic: Social Security (Box 9)
    - El Regimen de la Seguridad Social y sus Posibles Modificaciones, 1984; RISM 15849; Esquea Guerrero, Emmanuel T., 1944-; 15 pages; iv, 21 cm. (Box 9)
      Social security.; Dominican Republic.
  - Dominican Republic: Sugar Industry and Trade (Box 9)
    - Boletin Estadistico, 1983; RISM 20626; República Dominicana. Instituto Azucarero Dominicana; 18 pages; no content (Box 9)
      Sugar trade.; Dominican Republic.
    - The North American Sugar Industry in the Dominican Republic, 1870-1916, undated; RISM 20628; Bryan, Patrick E.; 22 pages (Box 9)
    - The Early Sugar Industry in Espanola, 1954; RISM 24645; Ratekin, Mervyn; p. 1-19. (Box 9)
      Dominican Republic.; Sugar trade.
  - Dominican Republic: Taxation (Box 9)
    - Taxation Information Exchange; Agreement Between the United States of America and the Dominican Republic, 1989; RISM 20629; United States. Department of State; 21 pages (Box 9)
      Taxation.; Dominican Republic.
  - Dominican Republic: Textile Industry and Trade (Box 9)
    - Trade in Textiles and Textile Products; Agreement Between the United States of America and the Dominican Republic, 1979-1980; RISM 20630; United States. Department of State; 4 pages (Box 9)
      Textile industry.; Dominican Republic.
- France (Box 9)
  - France: Indentured Servants (Box 9)
    - Les Departs d'Engages par Nantes pour l'Amerique, 1691-1733, undated; RISM 20641; Debien, Gabriel; p. 19-31. (Box 9)
      Indentured servants.; France.
- French Caribbean (Box 9)
  - French Caribbean: Agriculture (Box 9)
    - La Petite Propriete des Antilles Francaises dans la Crise de l'Economie de Plantation, 1970-1979; RISM 18150; Lasserre, Guy; p. 539-555. (Box 9)
      Caribbean, French-speaking.; Agriculture.
  - French Caribbean: Autonomy (Box 9)
    - Pour la Republique Unifiee des Travailleurs Antillais, 1978; RISM 16902; Groupe révolution socialiste; 20.0 (Box 9)
      Caribbean, French-speaking.; Autonomy.
  - French Caribbean: Bibliography (Box 9)
    - Early French West Indian Records in the Archives Nationales, 1941; RISM 18475; Ragatz, Lowell J. (Lowell Joseph), 1897-1978; p. 151-191 (Box 9)
      Caribbean, French-speaking.; Bibliography.
    - Les Travaux d'Histoire sur les Antilles Francaises: Chronique Bibliographique, 1959 et 1960, 1961; RISM 18476; Debien, Gabriel; p. 267-308. (Box 9)
    - Travaux d'Histoire Coloniale, 1: Notes d'Histoire Coloniale, undated; RISM 20635; 22 pages (Box 9)
      Bibliography.; Caribbean, French-speaking.
    - Etat des Recherches Anthropologiques aux Antilles Francaises, 1960-1972, RISM 24121; Lévy, Joseph Josy; 35 pages (Box 9)
  - French Caribbean: Blacks (Box 9)
    - Notes on the Negro in the French West Indies, 1940; RISM 20631; Achille, Louis; p. 20-23. (Box 9)
      Caribbean, French-speaking.
  - French Caribbean: Business Enterprises (Box 10)
    - Enquete Annuelle d'Entreprise dans les Services en 1988, 1990; Institut national de la statistique et des études économiques (France) (Box 10)
      Caribbean, French-speaking.; Business enterprises.
  - French Caribbean: Demography (Box 10)
    - Population des Departements Doutre-Mer: Recensement de 1967, 1968; RISM 17876; France. Ministère de l'intérieur; 12 pages; tables (Box 10)
      Demography.; Caribbean, French-speaking.
  - French Caribbean: Economic Conditions (Box 10)
    - 10 Ans d'Economie avec Antiane Eco: 1986-1996, RISM 20636; Institut national de la statistique et des études économiques (France). Direction interrégionale Antilles-Guyane; 18 pages (Box 10)
      Caribbean, French-speaking.; Economic conditions.
    - Foreign Economic Trends and Their Implications for the United States: Martinique, Guadeloupe, and French Guiana, 1970; RISM 20637; United States. Bureau of International Commerce; 14 pages (Box 10)
      Economic conditions.; Caribbean, French-speaking.
    - France d'Outre Mer, 1964; RISM 20638; 2 pages (Box 10)
  - French Caribbean: Family (Box 10)
    - Studies in Family Organization in the French Caribbean, 1957; RISM 10905; Murra, John V.; p. 372-378 (Box 10)
      Caribbean, French-speaking.; Family.
  - French Caribbean: Fisheries (Box 10)
    - Animaux Marins Comestibles des Antilles Francaises, 1958; RISM 18091; Morice, J.; p. 85-104. (Box 10)
      Caribbean, French-speaking.; Fisheries
  - French Caribbean: Folklore (Box 10)
    - Folklore des Antilles Francaises, undated (Box 10)
      Folklore.; Caribbean, French-speaking.
  - French Caribbean (Box 10)
    - Background Notes: French Antilles and Guiana, 1978-1983; RISM 20633; United States. Department of State; 2 items; 9/78, 11/83; no content (Box 10)
  - French Caribbean: Languages (Box 10)
    - Ecrire en Creole: Oralite et Ecriture aux Antilles; Review, 1996; RISM 23041; Schnepel, Ellen M.; p. 151-155. (Box 10)
      Caribbean, French-speaking.; Languages and languages.
    - Une Langue Marginale, Une Voix Feminine: Langue et Sexe dans les Etudes Creoles aux Antilles Francaises, 1992; RISM 23042; Schnepel, Ellen M.; p. 97-123. (Box 10)
      Languages and languages.; Caribbean, French-speaking.
    - The Other Tongue, The Other Voice: Language and Gender in the French Caribbean, 1993; RISM 23043; Schnepel, Ellen M.; p. 243-268. (Box 10)
  - French Caribbean: Literature (Box 10)
    - The Word: A Bridge to Authenticity in Simone Schwarz-Bart's 'The Bridge of Beyond', 1984; RISM 18477; Kavaliunas, Jolita; 17 pages (Box 10)
      History and criticism.; Caribbean, French-speaking.; Literature.
    - Literature of the French West Indies, 1956; RISM 20642; Koshland, Miriam G.; p. 274-277 (Box 10)
      Caribbean, French-speaking.; Literature.; History and criticism.
  - French Caribbean: Politics and Government (Box 10)
    - The European Islands: Haiti, French Caribbean, Surinam, 1971; RISM 24117; Latortue, Gérard R.; 19 pages (Box 10)
      Politics and government.; Caribbean, French-speaking.
  - French Caribbean: Population (Box 10)
    - Population Nee dans un Departement ou Territoire d'Outre-Mer et Residant en France Metropolitaine, 1969; RISM 17421; Institut national de la statistique et des études économiques (France); 8 pages (Box 10)
      Population.; Caribbean, French-speaking.
  - French Caribbean: Slavery (Box 10)
    - Citoyen ou Noir?: Periode Revolutionnaire et Esclavage, 1989; RISM 20643; 16 pages (Box 10)
      Slavery.; Caribbean, French-speaking.
    - La Revolution de 1789 a Maintenu en Guadeloupe et dans les Colonies le Code Noir et l'Esclavage des Negres, 1989; RISM 20644; Rodes, F.; 8 pages (Box 10)
      Caribbean, French-speaking.; Slavery.
    - Problematique d'une Histoire de l'Esclavage Urbain: Guadeloupe, Martinique, Guyane vers 1815-1848, 1984; RISM 20645; Adelaide-Merlande, Jacques; 20 pages (Box 10)
    - The French Slave Trade: An Overview, 2001; RISM 26735; Geggus, David Patrick; 16 pages; 16.0 (Box 10)
  - French Caribbean: Social Science Research (Box 10)
    - The State of Social Science Research in the French Caribbean, undated; RISM 24249; Schnepel, Ellen M.; 2 pages (Box 10)
      Caribbean, French-speaking.; Research (document genres).; Social sciences.
  - French Caribbean: Statistics (Box 10)
    - Antilles-Guyane en Chiffres: French West Indies and Guyana in Figures, 1995, RISM 20640; Institut national de la statistique et des études économiques (France). Direction interrégionale Antilles-Guyane; 24 pages (Box 10)